{
    "id": "1f2a94d218b541a0905b81b495b26211",
    "title": "Sentence Completion Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "This is the house where I was ……………..",
            "description": "Where means ‘in which’. Therefore, we don’t have to use the preposition ‘in’ at the end.",
            "answers": [
                "born",
                "born in",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0683a91300264a15a593f1fc749fd4da"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know a shop ……………… I can find watches?",
            "description": "Where can mean ‘at which’.",
            "answers": [
                "where",
                "at where",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "90fad9449c08423b9c10f72ce79d4bf5"
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know the reason …………….. she is angry with me?",
            "description": "Both why and for which are possible here.",
            "answers": [
                "for why",
                "why",
                "which",
                "for which"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "c8b2e769916446c388037c13ba1a9610"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will never forget the day ……………. I met Sally.",
            "description": "When can mean ‘on which’.",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "on when",
                "on which"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6888857d063d483fa930b66f2f366a07"
        },
        {
            "question": "Here is an article ……………….. might interest you.",
            "description": "A relative pronoun acts as the subject or object of the verb in the relative clause. It is therefore wrong to use another subject in the clause.",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "which it",
                "it which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "4656a2167e6f466bbc914564a474e55f"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the man ……………. my dog bit.",
            "description": "Both who and whom are possible here. Whom is used in a formal style.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "7362fe4aaabb484fab3bf0129582b447"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the sixth time you ………………… that question.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect tense in sentences constructed with 'this is the first / second / last / best etc'.",
            "answers": [
                "asked",
                "have asked",
                "had asked"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f3de8b242a024f92916f04d8353fd5d6"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t think …………….. she is coming.",
            "description": "Here the clause ‘that she is coming’ is the object of the verb think. We use ‘that’ to introduce noun clauses which act as objects.",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "so that"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3ddcd53c91694c71a0b9a3e77cf58707"
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………… tell Martha. She already knows.",
            "description": "Needn’t shows that there is no obligation.",
            "answers": [
                "needn't",
                "mustn't",
                "shouldn't"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "97edeb2b92234569bb6323dfe3324874"
        },
        {
            "question": "You …………….. tell Martha. I don’t want her to know.",
            "description": "Mustn’t shows prohibition.",
            "answers": [
                "needn't",
                "mustn't"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1b1b6f562b3d4d1ea444f4575ed7d51e"
        },
        {
            "question": "He wanted to know when .................................",
            "description": "In reported questions the subject normally comes before the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "was I leaving",
                "I was leaving"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9c3514d181f64a8883c63eb2a706e445"
        },
        {
            "question": "He suggested ......................... change my toothbrush.",
            "description": "Suggest cannot be followed by a to-infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "me to",
                "that I should",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "db380ea9d1e947e589a4a41281fe5719"
        }
    ]
}